어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri Martial Artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri Martial Artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi is here-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of the day
제일 강해질 날을
in the center of the world to become
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! the strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes a life dazzle
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes a life dazzle
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight the utmost with the stillness
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
His eyes shined! Musashi!!
쥬베에게서 에도토피아에서 열리는 연말 향례의 지팡구 무예 대회에 대해서 알게 된 무사시는
Jube told Musashi about the yearly Jipangu Martial Arts Competition.
창의 호조인과 한판 붙은 후, 미야코의 에도토피아를 꿈꾸며 여행을 계속하고 있었다.
After fighting against spear-wielding Houzouin, Musashi kept heading to Edotopia of Miyako.
무사시의 길에서 기다리는 것은 꽃인가 폭풍인가?
What is waiting in the road of Musashi? Is it a flower or a storm?
깨끗하고 가난한 쿠사리가마
Clean and Poor Kusarigama
무사시 씨!
Musashi!
오츠루!
Otsuru!
무사시 씨!
Musashi!
오츠루!
Otsuru!
무사시 씨!
Musashi!
오츠루!
Otsuru!
훌륭하게 되세요.
Be great!
응, 나, 무예 대회에서 우승했소! 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되었소!
Yes! I took the first place in the competition-dasu! I've became the number one Martial Artist in Jipangu!
축하해요.
Congratulations.
오츠루...
Otsuru...
멍청한 것! 꿈을 꾸기에도 이르다!
You idiot! You're even dreaming too early!
으악! 악몽이오!
This is a nightmare-dasu!
그건 내 코테츠이오!
Those are my Kotetsus!
돌려주시오!
Give those back-dasu!
뭣이오, 이 줄...
What's with this rope-dasu?
메롱이다!
Pfft!
야!
Hey!
화났소!
You made me mad-dasu!
멈추시오!
Stop right there!
달아날 생각 접으시오!
You aren't going anywhere-dasu!
기다리시오!
Stop!
또 같은 수에 넘어가지 않소!
I'm not falling over that again-dasu!
이 순간까지 이런 일을 한 나인데 방해에 지지 않소!
I have experienced too much be defeated to such disturbance-dasu!
순순히 칼을 돌려주시오!
Give it up and give my swords back-dasu!
꽤 하오...
He's pretty good-dasu.
아니아니, 감탄할 때가 아니오.
No, it's not the time to be surprised.
어디에 갔소?
Where did he go-dasu?
나오시오!
Come out!
숨다니 치사하오!
Hiding is unfair-dasu!
어디이오! 나오시오!
Where are you-dasu?! Show yourself-dasu!
거기!
Right there!
무슨 짓이오! 잠깐 멈추시오!
What are you doing-dasu? Stop-dasu!
갑자기 들이대다니 비겁하고 용서할 수 없소!
Attacking all of a sudden is cowardly and unforgivable-dasu!
뭐라? 비겁하다고?
What? Cowardly?
그쪽이야말로 사람이 풀을 베고 있는데 갑자기 큰 소리로 뛰어들다니 방해다!
You're the one who interfered, to dive to me while I'm cutting grasses!
바이켄
Baiken
풀을 베다니... 그게 낫이라는 것이오?
Cutting grasses... Is that something named sickle-dasu?
봐라!
Look!
어떻냐, 이제 알겠나?
Now you see?
한방에 많이 베어내다니 편리하오...
How convenient! You can cut many at once-dasu!
아, 일을 방해해서 미안하오.
Ah, sorry for interrupting-dasu.
나는 무사시라고 하오.
I am Musashi-dasu.
난 바이켄이라 한다.
I am Baiken.
칼을 가지고 있는 아이들을 보셨소?
Did you see those kids with swords-dasu?
칼을 가진 아이들?
Children with swords?
칼은 내 것이오.
Those swords are mine-dasu.
도난당했나?
Are they stolen?
아까 잠깐 낮잠을 자다가...
During I was taking a nap for a bit...
아이는 셋이었나!
Were there three children?
그, 그렇소.
Ri- right-dasu.
바이켄, 짚이는 게 있소?
Baiken, do you have suspects-dasu?
바이켄!
Baiken!
뭔가 사정이 있는 듯 하오.
He's up to something-dasu.
몇 번이고 말했을 텐데! 아직 모르겠나!
I told you countless times, and you still didn't get it?
그래도 형 칼 그렇게 가지고 싶어했다고 했으니까...
But bro, you said you wanted that much!
입 닫아라! 변명은 관둬라!
Close your mouth! No excuses!
입 닫아라! 사내 주제에 울지 마라!
Silence! A man must not cry!
자!
Now!
약속대로 손을 자르겠다.
I'll cut the hands as promised.
오하루. 넌 여자얘니까 이번은 용서해 주겠다.
Oharu. You'll be forgiven this time since you're only a girl.
잇켄, 니켄, 빨리 손을 내밀어라!
Ikken, Niken! Show your hands!
오하루! 넌 됐어!
Oharu! You don't need to!
형, 나라를 나올 때 모두 맹새했으니까...
Brother, we promised when we departed from the country.
지금부터는 힘을 모아서 하자고...
From now on, let's combine our powers, we promised.
죽는 것도, 사는 것도 같이라고...
We die and live together, we promised.
나 혼자 빠질 수는 없어...
I can't be excused.
오하루.
Oharu.
좋다. 알겠다. 죽는 것도 사는 것도 함께.
Alright, I get it. We die and live together.
그렇다면 형도 자르겠다.
Then I'll cut too.
형이 왜!
You don't have to!
너희들이 도둑질을 하고 만 것은 이 형의 책임도 있다.
I am responsible for your robbery too.
우리 형제는 죽는 것도 사는 것도 함께라고 했다.
We three live and die together.
그러니까...
So now we go...
멈추시오!
Stop!
잠깐! 멈추시오!
Stop! Stop right there!
무사시라고 했지.
Musashi, right?
훔쳐진 칼은 이것일 터.
This must be the stolen swords.
그건 내 것이지만...
Those are mine, but...
자, 가져가시오.
Take these back.
그래도 도둑질당한 것은 아니오.
But they aren't stolen-dasu.
뭐라?
What?
나, 낮잠을 자다가 방해가 되어 소나무에 기대 두었는데, 눈을 떴을 때 결국 완전히 잊고 떠나버렸소.
Actually, I rested my swords on a pine tree because it wasn't comfortable to bear my swords while sleeping,
but I forgot and left without them after waking up-dasu.
거짓말하지 마라!
Do not lie!
거짓말 아니오!
It's not a lie-dasu!
적어도 무예가가 무사의 혼이라고 불리는 칼을 두고 올 리가 없다!
A real Martial Artist will never forget his spirit - his sword!
그, 그래도...
B- but, still...
결국에 완전히 잊어버린 건 어쩔 수 없소.
I keep completely forgetting those stuff-dasu.
그럼 무사시는 가짜 무예가인가?
Are you calling yourself a fake Martial Artist, Musashi?
뭐라?
What did you say?!
칼을 잊다니 무예가일 리가 없다! 그냥 가짜일 뿐!
A real Martial Artist does not forget his own sword! Only an imposter does!
닥쳐, 닥치시오! 나는 보쿠덴을 스승으로 모신, 별거 생활을 했던 무예가이오!
Shut your mouth up! I am a Martial Artist who had to live apart to serve Bokuden as my master-dasu!
뭐라? 그 무토도리의 검성이라고 널리 알려진 보쿠덴의 제자?
What? A pupil of Bokuden, the master Martial Artist of mutodori?
나를 향해 가짜라고 하는 것은 뭐오, 가짜는!
How dare you call me a fake-dasu?!
무례를 저질렀다.
I've been impolite.
아, 알아 주겠다면... 별 사과할 것은...
If you understand, there's nothing special to apologize.
그럼 하나 부탁이 있소.
But I have a request.
에? 내가 할 수 있는 것이라면 무엇이든.
Huh? I'll do whatever I can-dasu.
한 수 가르쳐 달라.
Give me your best shot.
가르쳐 달라니? 연습이오?
Best shot? Do you want a practice match-dasu?
아니오. 진검승부요.
No. A match with real swords.
뭣이오?
What did you say-dasu?
싫나?
Is that a no?
아, 그런 건 아니지만...
No, that's not it, but...
할 수 있는 것이라면 무엇이든이라 말했지만, 그건 거짓이군!
You said that you'll do anything you can, but I can see that it was a flat-out lie!
사내는 두말하지 않소!
A man does not take back his words-dasu!
오래 기다리셨수다!
Sorry for making you wait!
바이켄, 그게 무기이오?
Baiken, is that your weapon?
그렇다. 쿠사리가마라 한다.
Right. It's a kusarigama.
쿠사리가마?
Kusarigama?
-해 보자!
-좋소!
-Let's do this!
-Right!
바이켄의 쿠사리가마에 무사시는 이길 수 있을 것인가? 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Will Musashi defeat Baiken's kusarigama? Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
형! 힘내!
Brother! Do your best!
형!
Brother!
조용히!
Silence!
이건 진검승부다!
This is a real match!
정신이 어지럽혀지니 목소리 내지 마라!
Don't say a thing or I'll be distracted!
지금부터 무슨 소리를 해도 일체 소용없다! 알겠나!
From now on, keep quiet and stay put! Understood?
네!
Got it!
형이 죽으면 우리도 죽으니까 말이야!
We'll die if you die!
참 어렵소...
How difficult it is...
무사시! 승부에 봐주기란 없다! 간다!
Musashi! There will be no going easy on you! Let's do this!
물론!
Of course!
무서운 뚝심!
What a strength!
이대로는 당하오. 이걸 어째야, 이걸...
This isn't good. What should I do-dasu, what should I...
제 몸을 희생할 때야말로 불리에서 벗어날 수 있다.
You may get out of difficulties only by sacrificing your own body.
자신의 목숨을 희생할 정도의 각오가 있으면 처음으로 승리를 얻을 수 있게 된다.
If you're prepared enough to throw your life for it, you will take your first victory.
형!
Brother!
저런!
No!
아야, 뭔 짓이오!
Ouch! What are you doing-dasu?!
멈춰라!
Stop that!
멈추라는 말이 안 들리나!
Don't you hear me?!
내가 졌다.
I lost.
아니오. 아직 승부가 나지 않았소.
No. The match isn't over yet-dasu.
아니아니, 손을 대지 말라고 말했는데 이렇게 되었으니...
No, that's not it. I've told them not to butt into the match, but...
이것도 형인 이 바이켄의 부덕의 소치이오.
This is also undesirable state brought about by my lack of virtue.
그런 것이 아니라 형제의 위기를 돕는 것은 당연하오!
No, it's reasonable to help a crisis of a sibling-dasu!
나는 저 아이들의 기분을 잘 이해하겠소.
I understand the feelings of those children-dasu.
부끄럽다. 그러나 형제에게 구해진 것은 진실이다. 그 말인즉슨, 그대로라면 졌단 것이오.
I am ashamed. But it's a true that my siblings helped me. That means, I would have been lost without their help.
그건 아직 모르오.
We don't know about that yet-dasu.
그러나...
But...
계속하지 않으면 알 수 없오!
We won't know if we don't continue-dasu!
너도 끈덕진 사람이다!
You are one verbose guy!
그런 바이켄이야말로!
Same for Baiken!
아무 반찬도 없지만, 보리죽은 충분히 있으니까 맘껏 먹어라.
We don't have any side dish, but you can eat this barley porridge as much as you want.
이렇게 모두 불가에 둘러앉아 먹는 것이 최고의 반찬이오! 맛있소.
Eating around a fireplace with everyone is the best side dish-dasu! It tastes great-dasu.
무사시 이상한 사람이네.
Musashi's a weird guy.
왜오?
Why-dasu?
그러니까 불이 반찬이라니... 나, 불로 구운 게 먹고 싶어.
How can be a fire a side dish? I want something roasted.
반찬 먹고 싶어. 매실엿이라도 괜찮으니까.
I'd like a side dish. Some pickled plum would be enough.
-오하루!
-뭐, 사실인데!
-Oharu!
-What? It's true!
그래도 말야, 매실엿이 없어도 매실엿에 대해 생각하는 것만으로 입 안이 시큼해지고 죽을 맛있게 먹을 수 있게 돼!
But still, even without pickled plums, only by thinking about those, I can feel the sourness and eat the porridge deliciously!
무사시. 아까는 네가 형제들을 감싸 주었는데, 보쿠덴의 제자라는 것을 듣고 그 실력을 시험해 보고 싶어져 승부를 보자고 해 미안했다.
Musashi, I have to apologize. You've covered for my siblings earlier in the day,
but after hearing from you that you're a pupil of Bokuden, I asked you for a match because I wanted to test your ability.
아니, 말도 안 되오. 나도 쿠사리가마로 싸워서 배울 수 있었소.
Nonsense-dasu. I could learn by fighting against an opponent with a kusarigama-dasu.
그래도 흥미로운 무기이오.
Anyway, it's an interesting weapon-dasu.
이것 말인가?
You mean this?
보쿠덴 스승님도 이런 무기가 있다고는 안 가르쳐 주셨소.
Master Bokuden didn't tell me about this weapon-dasu.
형이 발명했어!
My brother invented it!
오, 직접?
Oh, by himself?
사실 우리는 여기보다 북쪽에서 뭐든지 해 왔다.
We've been doing whatever we could at northern side of this place.
그 전란의 세상, 땀을 흘려 열심히 만든 농작물이나 밭도,
In the turbulent age, the crops and farms we made dripping with sweat have been destroyed numerous times,
몇 번이고 없어지며 전장으로 바뀌며 밟아 부수어지기도 하고, 우리 부모님도 죽임당하셨다.
and the fields were stamped and became a battlefield, taking away lives of our parents.
움직이면 안 돼.
Don't move.
가만히 있어.
Stay put.
그래도 아빠하고 엄마가!
But our dad and mom are...
지금 나가면 다 함께 죽어! 아빠도 엄마도 원수를 갚는 건 잊어라!
We all die if you go out! Forget about taking revenge for our parents!
이전 영주를 쓰러뜨리고, 새로운 영주가 된 다이묘는 곧잘 까딱하는 잔인하고 끔찍한 남자로
A new daimyo has taken down the previous lord and became one. He is easily flinching, cruel and horrible person
우리를 황무지로 몰아서, 가혹한 노동을 시켜서...
who drove us to a wasteland and made us do work in a brutal environment.
우리밖에 없었으니 책임을 다하지 못하고 곧잘 채찍으로 맞았다.
We alone were not enough to fulfill their demands, leaving us being often whipped.
필사적으로 도와준 형제자매의 상처투성이의 손을 보고
After seeing my hardworking siblings' hands full of wounds,
나는 이 낫으로 한번에 더 많은 풀을 베면 어떨까 하고 생각하고
I tried to devise a way to cut more grasses at once with this sickle,
그래서 큰 낫을 만들 생각을 했다.
and decided to make a big sickle.
어이, 네이놈! 일어서라!
Hey, you! Stand up!
어떻게든 봐 주세요!
Please forgive us!
방해하지 마라!
Do not get in the way!
나는 그 때 만큼이나 칼을 갖고 싶었던 적이 없었다.
I have never wanted a sword as much as back then.
사실은 나, 그 때부터 몰래 혼자 검술 수련을 하고 있었다.
Actually, I've been practicing swordsmanship in secret.
언젠가 진짜 무예가가 되어 다이묘를 쓰러뜨리고 부모님의 원수를 갚고 싶다 빌며.
Wishing to become the real Martial Artist, take down the daimyo, and have revenge for my parents.
그렇지만 제일 중요한 칼이 없다면 진짜 싸움은 불가능하니까.
But without the most important sword, a real fight is impossible.
난 생각했다.
I thought.
그 큰 낫을 무기로 어떻게 할 수 없을까 하고.
I thought to use that big sickle as a weapon.
그리고 여러 시도 끝에 낫에 사슬을 달아 추를 붙이면 어떨까 하고 생각했다.
And I finally came up with an idea to attach a weight to the sickle by using chains.
어느덧 나는 쿠사리가마를 자유롭게 쓸 수 있게 되었다.
Finally, I started to use kusarigama freely.
어떤 비바람이 강하게 치는 날 밤, 우리 형제는 국경을 넘어...
In one stormy night, we went over the country border and...
그랬소이까...
I see...
그러나 쿠사리가마를 잘 쓸 수 있게 되었다고 해도, 나는 정말로 칼을 이길 수 있을지 언제나 불안해서,
But even if I can use my kusarigama freely, I always was worried about being unable to defeat sword with it.
그것을 형제들이 알고 있으니까 실례를 하고 말았소.
Knowing that, that's why my siblings stole your swords.
아니, 칼은 확실히 무사의 혼. 잃어버린 쪽의 잘못이오.
Nope. A sword definitely a spirit of a Martial Artist-dasu. It is my fault, for losing it-dasu.
목이 말라도 도천의 물은 마시지 않는다.
(It is told that Confucius didn't drink from Tousen, 盜泉, literally thief pond, because of its name)
You don't drink from Tousen even when you're thirsty.
그것이 우리 형제의 맹새다.
That is the oath of our siblings.
그 맹새를 깼으니까...
And as we broke our oath...
이건 이 무사시가 용서하고, 앞으로는 하지 않으면 되는 것이오.
I, Musashi, will forgive that, and all you have to do is keep the oath again-dasu.
면목이 없다. 이 은혜는 언젠가...
I feel ashamed. I will return the favor someday.
그런 것보다도, 바이켄도 지팡구 무예 대회에...
More importantly, you should come to Jipangu Martial Arts Competition...
물론! 그걸 위해 오늘까지 노력해 왔다!
Of course! I've been training for that all the time!
또 하나 라이벌이 나타난 것이오!
I have a new rival-dasu!
우승결승전에서 만나고 싶소!
I hope to see you in the final match!
동감이오.
Agreed-dasu.
좋은 아침이오!
Good morning-dasu!
일어났군!
Good morning.
어라? 아이들은?
Huh? Where are the children?
밭에 가서 감자를 캐 온대.
They went gather potatoes from the field.
아직 사실은 다 자라진 않았지만, 무사시에게 반찬을 먹여주고 싶다며...
They aren't ripe yet, but they wanted to give you some real side dishes.
이야, 그렇게까지 생각해주지 않아도...
They're too kind for me...
형! 큰일이야!
Brother! We have a problem!
왜 그러나!
What is it?!
뭔 사무라이가 우리 밭을 마구 짓밟고 있어!
Some samurai is stamping on our field!
뭐라?!
What?!
네이놈들! 저리 비켜라!
You bastards! Get lost!
거긴 우리의 밭이다! 짓밟아 망치지 마라!
You're on our field! Do not trample down!
벌레같은 놈. 쳐라!
How annoying. Get him!
무사시! 불과 같이 도우러 가오!
Musashi! Now going to help, like a blaze-dasu!
몇 번이고 쓰려뜨려도 다음에 또 다음!
No matter how much I take down, they just keep coming!
좋아, 대장을 쓰러뜨리겠소!
Then I'll take down the head of them!
네이놈! 잡았다!
Got you, you brat!
뭐라?!
What?!
도망쳐!
Run away!
해냈어!
We did it!
지팡구 무예대회에서 재회를 약속하고 무사시는 한 발 먼저 에도토피아를 꿈꾼다.
Promising to meet again in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition, Musashi heads to Edotopia first.
그래도 바이켄의 쿠사리가마, 인물도 흥미롭고 무기도 또 흥미롭다.
Still, Baiken is interesting and his kusarigama is again, interesting.
무사시는 생각했다.
Musashi thought.
세상은 넓다. 그 넓은 세상에는 개성도 강하면 가슴도 강한 무예가가 아직 많이 있을 것이라고.
The world is broad. There will be still a lot of Martial Artists with strong personalities and strong heart.
미지의 상대에게 도전으로! 어린 무예가의 가슴이 뛰었다.
He will challenge unknown opponents! The young Martial Artist's heart was leaping.
허공의 주머니에 달이
Sometimes the moon jumps over
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
the pocket of the empty sky
큰 소리로 웃으면
Laugh loudly and
내일에는 아침이 와
a morning will come tomorrow
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Don't care too much about losing
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
Keep doing! Go for it!
맨손은 강해
A bare hand is strong
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
That's how life is! Look, a chance
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
follows us wagging its tail!
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
That's how future also is! Look, tomorrow
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
에도토피아를 꿈꾸는 도중, 상처를 입은 비둘기를 구했을 뿐인데, 말도 안 되는 패거리에게 노려지는 처지가 되었소.
Heading to Edotopia, simply by helping a wounded dove, I was being chased by some terrible gang of punks-dasu.
그 이름도 밤의 지배자, 한조! 무서운 닌자 군단과의 격투 후 라이벌 코지로까지도 휩쓸리고 말았소.
Their boss is Hanzo, the ruler of night! After a fight against frightening ninja corps, my rival Kojirō is now involved-dasu.
다음 이야기! 악의 한조, 살며서 다가오오!
Next story! Evil Hanzo Creeps
질풍노도의 활약을 보시오!
Be sure to check out the next stormy story-dasu!
다음 이야기
악의 한조, 살며시 다가오오
재미있게 보세요!
Next Story
Evil Hanzo Creeps
We hope you enjoy!